Papers from the Jim Walsh Collection
Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division, Library of Congress
Papers from the Jim Walsh Collection 1867-1987, and undated 1913-1985
Walsh, Jim, 1903-1990
23.58 linear feet
Recorded Sound Reference Center, Motion Picture, Broadcasting and Recorded Sound Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
The papers consist of correspondence, research files, photographs, scrapbooks, and other materials that form part of a larger collection of sound recordings and audio equipment assembled by journalist, radio host, and early recording collector Jim Walsh.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Deakins, Duane D.--Correspondence.; Debus, Allen G.--Correspondence.; Fargo, Milford H.--Correspondence.; Martindale, Jim (James V.), 1894-1981--Correspondence.; Riggs, Quentin--Correspondence.; Walsh, Jim, 1903-1990--Archives.; Walsh, Jim, 1903-1990--Photographs.; Walsh, Jim, 1903-1990.
Organizations
Jim Walsh Collection (Library of Congress)
Subjects
Collectors and collecting--Periodicals.; Collectors and collecting--United States--Archives.; Radio broadcasters--United States--Archives.; Sound recording industry.; Sound recordings--Collectors and collecting--United States--Archives.; Sound recordings--Collectors and collecting--United States.
Titles
Hobbies.; Walsh's wax works (Radio program)
Form/Genre
Advertisements.; Letters (Correspondence); Photographs.; Radio scripts.; Research notes.; Scrapbooks.; Writings.
Occupations
Entertainers--Photographs.; Entertainers.; Journalists--United States--Archives.; Musicians--Photographs.; Musicians.
Administrative Information
Collection Acquisition
This collection was donated to the Library of Congress by Jim Walsh in several increments between 1965 and 1987.
Additions
No further additions to the papers are expected.
Access Restrictions
The Papers from the Jim Walsh Collection are open for research. Researchers are cautioned to wear gloves when handling the materials.
Biographical Note
Journalist and collector Ulysses "Jim" Walsh (1903-1990) was born in Richmond, Virginia, on July 20, 1903. Best known for his "Favorite Pioneer Recording Artists" column that appeared in Hobbies magazine for over forty years, Walsh was recognized as one of the greatest collectors and authorities on popular acoustical-era recording artists and their recordings.
Walsh took an early interest in records, amassing a sizable collection and encyclopedic knowledge by the time he was a teenager. He began writing for newspapers in the late 1920s and had articles published in specialty magazines about recording artists. In 1934 Walsh moved to Johnson City, Tennessee, to become a reporter for the Johnson City Press, a job he would hold for nine years. Ulysses Walsh acquired the nickname "Jim," which he went by for the rest of his life, while working for the Press. While living in Tennessee in 1939, Walsh began hosting a radio program on local station WJHL. His program Walsh's Wax Works showcased old recordings from his collection and gave him a forum to discuss the lives and accomplishments of the artists whose music he played.
In 1942 Walsh began writing his column on early recording artists for Hobbies magazine. The column, originally called "The Coney Island Crowd," was soon renamed "Favorite Pioneer Recording Artists," the name under which it continued to be published through 1985. The column focused particularly on popular and vernacular recordings made before 1909, including jazz, humor, minstrel, and vaudeville; the focus was later broadened to include those artists who recorded before the dawn of electric recording techniques in 1925. In the following years, Walsh became well known among collectors as the authority on these early popular recordings. Although best known for his Hobbies columns, Walsh reached an even wider audience through his contributions to Variety and The New Yorker, among other publications.
In 1943 Walsh moved to the town of Vinton, Virginia, adjacent to Roanoke, and joined the staff of the Roanoke World News. At the same time, he made connections with radio station WDBJ in Roanoke and resurrected his show Walsh’s Wax Works. After a short run, he moved the show to radio station WSLS, where it was broadcast through 1960.
Walsh continued to collect recordings, playback equipment, and reference resources such as record catalogs, magazines, and advertisements. For many of his favorite artists, such as Billy Murray, Al Jolson, Harry Lauder, and Vernon Dalhart, he collected nearly every recording they had ever made. Walsh became a great correspondent, fostering relationships with recording artists, collectors, dealers, and his readers and listeners. In later years, he traveled to gatherings of early recording artists and collectors, meeting many of the artists he had idolized as a child.
Walsh was a lifetime bachelor and had a deep devotion to his many cats. He gave updates on his "family of cats" in much of his correspondence and occasionally in his columns; he even arranged to have poems published under the name of his favorite cat: Professor Plum Duff Walsh, Ph.D.
During the late 1970s and 1980s Walsh’s health declined, and he complained of memory loss. In May 1985 his last column was published in Hobbies. He died in 1990 after several years of residence in nursing homes. Walsh was posthumously awarded the first Lifetime Achievement Award given by the Association for Recorded Sound Collections (ARSC) in 1991.
Scope and Content Note
Jim Walsh devoted his life to collecting, researching, and writing about early popular recordings and recording artists. These papers make up part of the much larger Jim Walsh Collection of early recordings, audio equipment, and related items donated by Walsh to the Library of Congress between 1965 and 1987. The complete collection consists of approximately 40,000 discs, 500 cylinders, and 23 early phonographs. Recordings in the collection are primarily of popular and vernacular music recorded during the acoustical era (pre-1926). It includes a nearly complete run of 5,000 to 6,000 Edison "Diamond Disc" recordings as well as many early Edison cylinders.
This portion of the collection consists of documents and other paper records that relate to Walsh's career and collecting efforts. Included are letters with prominent artists and collectors, research notes, photographs of performers, scripts for Walsh’s radio shows, drafts of his columns and articles, clippings, bound journals, advertisements, and ephemera. The papers also hold a wealth of biographical information about Jim Walsh, including a diary, scrapbooks, photographs, and writings.
Collection Arrangement
The papers are arranged in eight series:
Series 1: Correspondence/Research Files, 1913-1987, and undated
Series 2: Writings, circa 1942-circa 1975
Series 3: Radio Scripts, 1943-1954, and undated
Series 4: Ephemera, 1915-1972, and undated
Series 5: Photographs, 1867-circa 1985
Series 6: Oversized Materials, 1914-1953, and undated
Series 7: Scrapbooks, 1892-1939, and undated
Series 8: Bound Publications, 1901-1977, and undated
http://lccn.loc.gov/2008647469
Container List
- Series 1. Correspondence/Research Files, 1913-1987, and undated, 2.94 linear feet
  Consists of correspondence, notes, copies of birth and death records, obituaries, and other materials collected by Walsh as he researched performers and recordings. The Correspondence subseries consists of Jim Walsh’s written communications with collectors, dealers, experts, record companies, readers, and listeners. Many of the letters consist of requests for information, responses to requests for information, discussions concerning equipment, inquiries about particular recordings or companies, and potential purchases or trades. Frequent correspondents include Duane Deakins, Allen Debus, Milford Fargo, Jim Martindale, and Quentin Riggs.
  Research files consist of information about individuals, recordings, and subjects. Many of the files concerning recording artists or personalities include correspondence with or about the performers, and this is complemented by a wealth of other biographical information. Resources include copies of birth and death records, newspaper and magazine clippings, record lists, obituaries, research notes, brief biographies written by Walsh, and other miscellaneous items. Researchers can find photographs of many of the individuals represented here in Series 5.
  The series is divided into two subseries: Correspondence and Research Files. Correspondence is filed alphabetically by correspondent’s name; a few miscellaneous and unidentified folders are placed at the end of the subseries. Research files are arranged alphabetically by artist or subject.
  - Correspondence
    - Brooks, Tim, 1968, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Burt, Leah Brodbeck Stenzel, 1972-1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Columbia Phonograph Co., 1929-1957 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Crossett, Glenn "Curly," 1948-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Deakins, Duane D., 1953-1961 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - Debus, Allen, 1942-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - Dethlefson, Ronald, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Dorian, Frank, 1930-1934 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Edison, Thomas A. Co., 1923-1975 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Includes copies of correspondence from 1921 to 1922.
    - Fargo, Milford, 1957-1961 (Box 1, Folder 12-13)
    - Fasset, Stephen, 1940-1948, and undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Favia-Artsay, Aida, 1953-1962 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Forman, Ed, 1954-1957 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Gennet Records, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Hansen, Barry (1941-) ("Dr. Demento"), 1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Harrington, Fred, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Hearne, Will Roy, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - John Beiling Day Party, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Johnston, Stanley, 1952, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Kattenberg, Burns M., 1933 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Library of Congress, 1963-1987 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - Lincoln, Thomas R., 1942-1952 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - MacNamara, Daniel I., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Marks, Herbert, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Martindale, Jim (James V.) (1894-1981), 1938-1980 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
    - Miller, Phillip, 1953-1954 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - Moran, Bill, 1944, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Odell, L. Brevoort, 1948-1969, and undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Operaphone Records, 1918 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Riggs, Quentin, 1945-1985 (Box 2, Folder 34-39)
    - Rust, Brian A. L., 1957-1959, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 40)
    - Stevens, Lou, 1947-1949 (Box 2, Folder 41)
    - Victor Talking Machine Co./RCA Victor Co., 1925-1931 (Box 2, Folder 42)
    - Welch, Walter L. (Walter Leslie), 1942, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - Woodymay Record Co., 1941-1949, and undated (Box 2, Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous collectors, 1935-1974, and undated (Box 2, Folder 45-46)
    - Miscellaneous publishers and editors, 1931-1957, and undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
    - Miscellaneous readers and listeners, 1929-1979 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - Miscellaneous requests for information, 1933-1978, and undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
    - Unidentified correspondents, 1948-1970 (Box 2, Folder 50)
  - Research files
    - Alexander, George (Clifford A. Wiley), 1954-1956 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - Austin, Gene, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - Baker, Elsie (1886-1958), 1948-1975 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - Ball, Rae Eleanor, undated (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - Banta, Frank E. (1897-1969), 1956-1978 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Barbour, Inez (Mrs. Henry Hadley), 1955 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - Belmont, Joseph (1876-1949), 1949 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - Benzler, Albert, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - Berlin, Irving (1888-1989), 1948-1958 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Bieling, John H. (1869-1948), 1948 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Brown, Albert Edmund, 1929-1955 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Busch, Lou (Joe “Fingers" Carr), 1955 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Byrd, Harry Flood (1887-1966) (Senator), 1975 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Caesar, Irving (1895-1996), 1957, and undated (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Cali, John, circa 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Cameron, Grace, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Campbell, Albert, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Chalmers, Thomas, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Clarence, Edward, undated (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Clark, Helen, 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 70)
    - Collins, Arthur, 1942-1948 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Cowles, Eugene (1860-1948), undated (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Crumit, Frank (and Julia Sanderson), 1943-1975 (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Dadmun, Royal, 1975, and undated (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Dalhart, Vernon (1883-1948), 1970-1977, and undated (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - D’Almaine, Charles (1871-1943), 1951-1957 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Dann Trio, The, 1973-1977 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Davis, Joe (1896-1978), 1977, and undated (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Diero, Guido and Pietro, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - De Leath, Vaughn, 1934, 1943, and undated (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Dickens, Charles (1812-1870), 1954-1957 (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Dudley, George, 1950-1956 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Duncan Sisters, The, 1952-1955 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Duprez, Fred, 1938-1952, and undated (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Edison, Thomas A. (Thomas Alva) (1847-1931), 1916-1924 (Box 3, Folder 85-87)
      Copies.
    - Elman, Mischa (1891-1967), 1958-1959 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Fagan, Sibyl Sanderson, 1919-1927 (Box 4, Folder 89)
      Photocopies.
    - Farley, James, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 90)
    - Fields, Arthur, 1949-1953 (Box 4, Folder 91)
    - Freemantel, Frederic, 1923, 1940-1951 (Box 4, Folder 92)
    - Gilbert, L. Wolfe (Louis Wolfe) (1886-1970), 1953-1963 (Box 4, Folder 93)
    - Gillham, Art (1895-1961), 1957 (Box 4, Folder 94)
    - Girard, Armand (Rounders Quintet), 1970 (Box 4, Folder 95)
      Photocopy.
    - Glenn, Wilfred, 1970-1972 (Box 4, Folder 96)
    - Green, Lew (Green Brothers), 1959-1961 (Box 4, Folder 97)
    - Greene, Gene, 1956-1957 (Box 4, Folder 98)
    - Gruppe, Paulo M., 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 99)
    - Hall, Arthur, 1948-1950, and undated (Box 4, Folder 100)
    - Hall, Wendell, 1952-1964 (Box 4, Folder 101)
    - Handy, W. C. (William Christopher) (1873-1958), 1951-1956 (Box 4, Folder 102)
    - Hare, Ernest See Jones, Billy
    - Harlan, Byron G., 1948-1951 (Box 4, Folder 103)
    - Harrison, Charles, 1940-1957 (Box 4, Folder 104)
    - Hart, Chas. (Charles), 1953-1964 (Box 4, Folder 105)
    - Harvey, Morton, 1949-1955 (Box 4, Folder 106)
    - Hatlo, Jimmy, 1941, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 107)
    - Helena, Edith (1876-1956), 1948-1956 (Box 4, Folder 108)
    - Hindermyer, Harvey W., 1947-1957 (Box 4, Folder 109)
    - Hooley, William (1861-1918), 1949 (Box 4, Folder 110)
    - Howard, Joseph E. (Joseph Edgar) (1878-1961), 1944, and undated (Box 4, Folder 111)
    - Hunting, Russell, 1944-1950 (Box 4, Folder 112)
    - Irwin, May (1862-1938), 1939 (Box 4, Folder 113)
    - James, Lewis, undated (Box 4, Folder 114)
    - Jaudas, Eugene, 1928 (Box 4, Folder 115)
    - Jones, Ada, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 116)
    - Jones, Billy (1889-1940) and Ernest Hare, 1931-1959 (Box 4, Folder 117)
    - Jones, Spike (1911-1965), 1948-1951 (Box 4, Folder 118)
    - Jordan, Mary, 1923-1958 (Box 4, Folder 119)
    - José, Richard (1862-1941), 1915-1950 (Box 4, Folder 120)
    - Kaiser, Marie, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 121)
    - Kaufman, Irving (1890-1976), 1940-1967, and undated (Box 5, Folder 122)
    - Keefe, Andrew, 1976 (Box 5, Folder 123)
    - Kelso, Mayme (Mary L. Bent), 1979 (Box 5, Folder 124)
    - Kimmel, John, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 125)
    - Kline, Olive, 1959-1976 (Box 5, Folder 126)
    - Kronold, Harris, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 127)
    - Laska, Edward (1894-1959), 1951-1955, and undated (Box 5, Folder 128)
    - Lauder, Harry, Sir (1870-1950), 1924 (Box 5, Folder 129)
    - Laurie, Joe (1893-1954), 1943-1954, and undated (Box 5, Folder 130)
    - Leachman, Silas, 1954-1955, and undated (Box 5, Folder 131)
    - Lloyd, Alice (1873-1949) (Alice Wood), 1949 (Box 5, Folder 132)
    - Lucey, Leola, 1919-1921 (Box 5, Folder 133)
    - Lulu Belle & Scotty, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 134)
    - Luther, Frank, 1946-1953 (Box 5, Folder 135)
    - MacDonough, Harry (1871-1931), 1931-1932, 1948 (Box 5, Folder 136)
    - Madeira, Addison, 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 137)
    - Manhattan Ladies Quartet of New York City, 1913 (Box 5, Folder 138)
    - Mann, Estella Louise (1871-1947), 1951 (Box 5, Folder 139)
    - Marimba/xylophone, 1970-1972 (Box 5, Folder 140)
    - Marshall, Henry, 1952-1959 (Box 5, Folder 141)
    - Meeker, Edward (1874-1937), 1933, 1944, and undated (Box 5, Folder 142)
    - Meyer, John A., 1971 (Box 5, Folder 143)
    - Miller, Bob (1895-1955), 1931, 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 144)
    - Morse, Dolly, 1952 (Box 5, Folder 145)
    - Morse, Theodore F. (1873-1924), 1952 (Box 5, Folder 146)
    - Morton, Ed, 1951-1952, and undated (Box 5, Folder 147)
    - Murray, Billy, 1932-1975, and undated (Box 5, Folder 148)
    - Nealy, Arthur, 1967, and undated (Box 5, Folder 149)
    - Norworth, Jack, 1942-1959 (Box 5, Folder 150)
    - Oakland, Will (1883-1956), 1940-1956, and undated (Box 5, Folder 151-152)
    - O’Connor, George (1874-1946), 1943-1946 (Box 5, Folder 153)
    - O’Hara, Geoffrey, 1960-1965 (Box 5, Folder 154)
    - Ossman, Vess L., 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 155)
    - Parvis, Taurino (born 1879), 1955-1956 (Box 6, Folder 156)
    - Person, Alice, undated (Box 6, Folder 157)
    - Preston, Walter (baritone), 1970 (Box 6, Folder 158)
    - Quinn, Dan W., 1932-1937, and undated (Box 6, Folder 159)
    - Raymond, Maud, undated (Box 6, Folder 160)
    - Reser, Harry, 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 161)
    - Rice, Gladys, 1973-1977 (Box 6, Folder 162)
    - Robinson, Bill (1878-1949) (Bojangles), 1949 (Box 6, Folder 163)
    - Robison, Carson, 1929-1955 (Box 6, Folder 164)
    - Robyn, Alfred G. (Alfred George) (1860-1935), 1949 (Box 6, Folder 165)
    - Romain, Manuel, 1946-1951 (Box 6, Folder 166)
    - Rose, Eugene, 1947-1952, and undated (Box 6, Folder 167)
    - Sadler, Josie, undated (Box 6, Folder 168)
    - Sanderson, Julia See Crumit, Frank
    - Scanlan, Walter (Van Brunt, Walter), 1935-1954, and undated (Box 6, Folder 169)
    - Seltsam, William H., circa 1930-1935 (Box 6, Folder 170)
    - Shaw, Elliott, 1954, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 171)
    - Shilkret, Nathaniel (1895-), 1952, 1961 (Box 6, Folder 172)
    - Silver, Monroe, 1940 (Box 6, Folder 173)
    - Smalle, Ed, 1953-1955, and undated (Box 6, Folder 174)
    - Smeck, Roy, 1977 (Box 6, Folder 175)
    - Smith, Whistling Jack, 1950, 1958 (Box 6, Folder 176)
    - Spaeth, Sigmund Gottfried (1885-1965), 1949-1955, and undated (Box 6, Folder 177)
    - Spalding, Albert (1888-1953), 1953 (Box 6, Folder 178)
    - Spencer, Elizabeth, 1951, and undated (Box 6, Folder 179)
    - Spencer, Grace (1872-1952), 1947-1957 (Box 6, Folder 180)
    - Spencer, Len (1867-1914), 1937-1979, and undated (Box 6, Folder 181)
    - Stanley, Aileen (1893-1982), 1959, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 182)
    - Stanley, Frank C. (1868-1910), 1945, and undated (Box 6, Folder 183)
    - Sterling, Louis, 1948 (Box 6, Folder 184)
    - Stevenson, Elsie, 1978, and undated (Box 6, Folder 185)
    - Stewart, Cal, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 186)
    - Sundelius, Marie, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 187)
    - Talley, Harry L., 1952-1956, and undated (Box 6, Folder 188)
    - Tollefson Trio, 1912, 1963 (Box 6, Folder 189)
      Photocopies of 1912 and 1963 materials.
    - Thomas, John Charles (1891-1960), 1971 (Box 6, Folder 190)
    - Trix, Helen, 1950-1951, and undated (Box 6, Folder 191)
    - Tucker, Sophie (1884-1966), 1953-1966 (Box 6, Folder 192)
    - Van, Gus (1887-1968), 1951 (Box 7, Folder 193)
    - Van Eps, Fred (1878-1960), 1950-1958, and undated (Box 7, Folder 194)
    - Vance, Clarice, undated (Box 7, Folder 195)
    - Walker, Ray, 1944-1960, and undated (Box 7, Folder 196-197)
    - Walsh, Jim (1903-1990), 1940-1985 (Box 7, Folder 198)
      Biographical information.
    - Watawaso, Princess, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 199)
      Photocopies of 1969 materials.
    - Wheeler, Dan, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 200)
    - Wheeler, Fred, 1948, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 201)
    - White, Edna (born 1892), 1957-1980, and undated (Box 7, Folder 202)
    - White, Joseph M. ("The Silvermasked Tenor"), 1953-1954 (Box 7, Folder 203)
    - Whitehouse, Fred, 1951-1953, and undated (Box 7, Folder 204)
    - Whitlock, Billy, 1949-1950, and undated (Box 7, Folder 205)
    - Whitney, Edwin M., 1951-1960 (Box 7, Folder 206)
    - Wiedoeft, Rudy, 1964-1977 (Box 7, Folder 207)
    - Wilder, Marshall, undated (Box 7, Folder 208)
    - Wills, Nat M., 1916, and undated (Box 7, Folder 209)
      Mostly photocopies of 1916 material.
    - Wodehouse, P. G. (Pelham Grenville) (1881-1975), 1975 (Box 7, Folder 210)
    - Wood, De, 1952-1953 (Box 7, Folder 211)
    - “Wreck of the Old 97," 1951 (Box 7, Folder 212)
    - Young, Victor (1889-1968) and Young, Helen (Davis), 1952, and undated (Box 7, Folder 213)
    - Miscellaneous collection documentation, undated (Box 7, Folder 214)
    - Miscellaneous notes on recording artists, undated (Box 7, Folder 215)
- Series 2. Writings, circa 1942-circa 1975, and undated, .42 linear feet
  This collection of Jim Walsh’s writings dates from approximately 1942 through 1975, but the majority are undated. Most of the items found in this series are drafts of articles or columns Walsh wrote for Hobbies, Variety, or The New Yorker, but several bear no indication of their intended publisher. The articles relate primarily to the history of recording and more specifically address subjects such as Edison’s inventions, songs on particular themes, recording artist biographies, and record collecting in general. One folder of writings on miscellaneous topics is included. Copies of indexes to Walsh’s Hobbies column "Favorite Pioneer Recording Artists" can also be found here.
  Writings are arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Edison, Thomas A. (Thomas Alva) (1847-1931), undated (Box 8, Folder 216)
  - History of recording, undated (Box 8, Folder 217)
  - Holiday songs, undated (Box 8, Folder 218)
  - Indexes to "Favorite Pioneer Recording Artists" in Hobbies, undated (Box 8, Folder 219)
  - Political songs, undated (Box 8, Folder 220)
  - Record collecting and collectors, undated (Box 8, Folder 221)
  - Recording artists (biographical), undated (Box 8, Folder 222-223)
  - Miscellaneous, undated (Box 8, Folder 224)
- Series 3. Radio Scripts, 1943-1954, and undated, .63 linear feet
  Series 3 includes scripts for Walsh’s regular broadcasts on radio stations WDBJ and WSLS in Roanoke, Virginia. The majority of the scripts found here date from 1943 through 1949 and are for Walsh’s Wax Works; many of the scripts include separate playlists. Walsh’s shows usually focused on particular themes (for example, songs about girls named Sue), early comedians, early Edison cylinders, or holiday songs. Many of the shows showcased a particular recording artist or composer; an index to these shows is available in the Recorded Sound Reference Center at the Library of Congress. The few scripts available for Walsh’s Sunlight and Shadows show date from 1947 and 1948. A folder of unidentified and partial scripts is included at the end of the series.
  Radio scripts are arranged alphabetically and thereunder by date.
  - Sunlight and Shadows radio scripts, 1947-1948 (Box 9, Folder 225)
  - Walsh’s Wax Works radio scripts, 1943 May-1946 December (Box 9, Folder 226-239)
  - Walsh’s Wax Works radio scripts, 1947 January-1949 August (Box 10, Folder 240-249)
  - Miscellaneous and unidentified broadcasts, 1948, 1954, and undated (Box 10, Folder 250)